<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
layout: page
subheadline: "Johanna Eugenio"
title: "Bubonic Plague"
teaser: "This blog post includes details about the plague in Egypt and how prevalent it was in certain areas. "
date: 2016-12-11 <!--- date of post submission --->
categories:
- Serial 
author: JohannaEugenio <!--- all one word --->
tags:
- Plague
- Bubonic Plague
- Diseases
- Sickness

header: no
image: blogpostimage-table.png <!--- for image-name.png, substitute name you've given your image file --->
title: blog-images/blogpostimage-table.jpg
thumb: blog-images/blogpostimage-table.jpg
homepage: blog-images/blogpostimage-table.jpg
caption: This is an image of a table that shows the amount of times specific cases, deaths, and recoveries/cures the Plague has reported in certain cities. <!--- info about the image, such as date of issue --->
caption_url: <!--- link-to-page-containing-text? --->
---
When reading throughout the Egyptian Gazette I came across many different diseases that Egypt was facing during 1905. Such as Enteric Fever, Bubonic Plague, or even Cattle Plague. It was interesting to see
the different diseases that were prevalent in Egypt during this time. Prior to reading this I had not realized the Plague was something countries were still having to deal with 
during the 1900's. As for my serial question I decided to focus on one specific disease, the Plague. My question being "How often did the Egyptian Gazette report specific cases of the Plague in 1905? 
And how many cases were specifically reported compared to the actual amount of cases that occurred?" I got my data for this question
by starting out by doing simple query searches. I used the //div[@type="item"][contains(., 'insertword')] to search the amount of divs that included 
topics such as "diseases", "plague", "enteric disease", and so on to see which disease was reported more throughout the newspaper.
I created a table that included the specific word I searched and how many results I got back from that specific term.
For "Plague" I got back 82 results compared to the 4 for "enteric", therefore I decided to focus on the more predominant disease.
With the 82 results I received back from my search I used this data as a reference point and found out what cities reported cases of the plague, deaths,
and recoveries and how many times it was reported in that specific place. This will allow me to compare and contrast and add up the amount of specific cases reported.
With these results I will make a pie chart showing how many regular cases were reported, the deaths, and cures/recoveries during 1905. I will then make a bar graph showing the 
amount of specific cases reported in the Egyptian Gazette during 1904 and 1905 compared to the overall actual cases that actually occured. This serial question will
allow me to emphasize how prevalent the Plague was during 1905 and how often it was reported in this newspaper.


If you wish to include a second image (other than your main image, which you indicate in the header), insert a reference in the following format into the body of your post:

![image name](https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/image-name.png?raw=true)
